A Guide to the Virginia War History Commission, 1915-1931
Library of Virginia
- Series XIV: Second Virginia Council of Defense, 1917-1921, 1923-1924
  - Subseries A: Source Material
    - Health (42a) (Box 259, Folder 9)
    - [Local Woman's Committees] (42a) See Also Oversize Box 2 (Box 259, Folder 10)
    - (42b) (Box 259, Folder 11)
    - Local Councils (42c) (Box 259, Folder 12)
    - Local Councils (42d) (Box 259, Folder 13)
    - (42e-f) (Box 260, Folder 1)
    - War Work (42g) (Box 260, Folder 2)
    - War Work (42h) (Box 260, Folder 3)
    - War Work (42k-l) (Box 260, Folder 4)
    - Labor (43a) (Box 260, Folder 5)
    - Labor (43b) (Box 260, Folder 6)
    - Labor - Industrial Training (43c) (Box 260, Folder 7)
    - Labor - Vocational Training (43c) (Box 260, Folder 8)
    - Labor (43d) (Box 260, Folder 9)
    - Housing/Industry (43e) (Box 260, Folder 10)
    - Labor (43g) (Box 260, Folder 11)
    - Housing/Industry (43g) (Box 260, Folder 12)
    - Soldiers (43h) (Box 260, Folder 13)
    - Soldiers (43k) (Box 260, Folder 14)
    - Soldiers (43m) (Box 260, Folder 15)
    - Soldiers (43n) (Box 260, Folder 16)
    - Soldiers (44a) (Box 261, Folder 1)
    - Soldiers (44b) (Box 261, Folder 2)
    - Soldiers (44c) (Box 261, Folder 3)
    - Soldiers (44d) (Box 261, Folder 4)
    - Livestock (44e) (Box 261, Folder 5)
    - Livestock (44g) (Box 261, Folder 6)
    - [Livestock] (44h, i, j) (Box 261, Folder 7)
    - [Livestock] (44k, l) (Box 261, Folder 8)
    - [Livestock] (44m) (Box 261, Folder 9)
    - Negro Activities (44n) (Box 261, Folder 10)
    - Liberty Loan and War Savings (45a) (Box 261, Folder 11)
    - Conservation (45b) (Box 261, Folder 12)
    - War Photographs (45c) (Box 261, Folder 13)
    - Speakers Bureau (45d) (Box 261, Folder 14)
    - Transportation (45e) (Box 261, Folder 15)
    - Education (45g) (Box 261, Folder 16)
    - Education (45h) (Box 261, Folder 17)
    - Health-Nursing (45k) (Box 261, Folder 18)
    - [Miscellaneous - Indexed] (45m) (Box 261, Folder 19)
    - [Not Indexed] (45m) (Box 261, Folder 20)
    - Council of National Defense (46a) (Box 262, Folder 1)
    - Local Councils (46b) (Box 262, Folder 2)
    - (46c) (Box 262, Folder 3)
    - Home Guards (46d) (Box 262, Folder 4)
    - Health (46e) (Box 262, Folder 5)
    - Home Guards (46g) (Box 262, Folder 6)
    - [Co-operative Education Association of Virginia] (46h-j) (Box 262, Folder 7)
    - Conservation (46k) (Box 262, Folder 8)
    - Fire Prevention (46m) (Box 262, Folder 9)
    - Health (46n) (Box 262, Folder 10)
    - (46p) (Box 262, Folder 11)
    - Health (46r) (Box 262, Folder 12)
    - Health (46s) (Box 262, Folder 13)
    - Livestock (47a) (Box 262, Folder 14)
    - Labor (47c) (Box 262, Folder 15)
    - Industry (47d) (Box 262, Folder 16)
    - Soldiers (47e) (Box 262, Folder 17)
    - Patriotism and Propaganda (47h-k) (Box 262, Folder 18)
    - Patriotism and Propaganda (47h-k) (Box 263, Folder 1)
    - Photographs (48) (Box 263, Folder 2)
    - Photographs [Red Cross; Dupont, Hopewell, Virginia](48) (Box 263, Folder 3)
    - Photographs, Newport News Shipbuilding and Dry Dock, Co. (48) (Box 263, Folder 4)
    - Photographs, Newport News Shipbuilding (48) (Box 263, Folder 5)
    - Reconstruction/Soldiers (48a) (Box 263, Folder 6)
    - Labor (48b) See Also Oversize Box 2 (Box 263, Folder 7)
    - Council of National Defense (48c) (Box 263, Folder 8)
    - Agriculture/Labor (48d) (Box 263, Folder 9)
    - (49) (Box 263, Folder 10)
    - (49) (Box 264, Folder 1)
    - (49) (Box 264, Folder 2)
    - (50a) (Box 264, Folder 3)
    - (50b) (Box 264, Folder 4)
    - (50c) (Box 264, Folder 5)
    - (50d) (Box 264, Folder 6)
    - (50e-f) (Box 264, Folder 7)
    - Council of National Defense (51/52) (Box 264, Folder 8)
    - Council of National Defense (51/52) (Box 264, Folder 9)
    - Council of National Defense (51/52) (Box 265, Folder 1)
    - Council of National Defense (51/52) (Box 265, Folder 2)
    - Council of National Defense (51/52) (Box 265, Folder 3)
    - Council of National Defense (53) (Box 265, Folder 4)
    - Council of National Defense (53) (Box 265, Folder 5)
    - Council of National Defense (53) (Box 265, Folder 6)
    - Council of National Defense (53) (Box 265, Folder 7)
    - Council of National Defense (54) (Box 266, Folder 1)
    - Council of National Defense (54) (Box 266, Folder 2)
    - Council of National Defense (54) (Box 266, Folder 3)
    - Council of National Defense (51/52) (Box 266a, Folder 1)
    - Council of National Defense (51/52) (Box 266a, Folder 2)
    - Council of National Defense (51/52) (Box 266a, Folder 3)
    - Council of National Defense - Miscellaneous Bulletins (51, 52, 53, 54) (Box 266a, Folder 4)
    - Council of National Defense - Miscellaneous Bulletins (51, 52, 53, 54) (Box 266a, Folder 5)
    - Council of National Defense - Miscellaneous Bulletins (51, 52, 53, 54) (Box 266b, Folder 1)
    - Council of National Defense - Miscellaneous Bulletins (51, 52, 53, 54) (Box 266b, Folder 2)
    - Council of National Defense - Miscellaneous Bulletins (51, 52, 53, 54) (Box 266b, Folder 3)
    - [Wood] (55) (Box 266b, Folder 4)
    - [Wood] (55) (Box 266b, Folder 5)
    - [Wood] (55) (Box 266b, Folder 6)
    - [Wood] (55) (Box 266b, Folder 7)
  - Subseries B: Records
    - Fair Prices - Correspondence (Box 267, Folder 1)
    - Governor on Fair Prices - Hugh B. Sproul (Box 267, Folder 2)
    - Fair Prices - Information and Complaints Concerning Fair Prices (Box 267, Folder 3)
    - Fair Prices - General Publicity on Fair Prices (Box 267, Folder 4)
    - Bills and Receipts (Box 268, Folder 1)
    - Conservation (Box 268, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, Executive Secretary - Keiley, Charles R., N.D. (Box 268, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, Executive Secretary, January 1918 - April 1918 (Box 268, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, Executive Secretary - Keiley, Charles R., May-December 1918 (Box 268, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, Field Secretary - Keiley, Charles R., January-June 1919 (Box 268, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, Field Secretary - Keiley, Charles R., July 1919 (Box 268, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, Field Secretary - Keiley, Charles R., August-October 1919 (Box 268, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, Field Secretary - Keiley, Charles R., November-December 1919 (Box 268, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, Field Secretary - Keiley, Charles R., January 1920 (Box 269, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, Field Secretary - Keiley, Charles R., February 1920 (Box 269, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, Field Secretary - Keiley, Charles R., March 1920 (Box 269, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, Field Secretary - Keiley, Charles R., April-May 1920 (Box 269, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, Field Secretary - Keiley, Charles R., June-July 1920 (Box 269, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, Field Secretary - Keiley, Charles R., August-September 1920 (Box 269, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, Field Secretary - Keiley, Charles R., October 1920-October 1921 (Box 269, Folder 7)
    - War History - Correspondence to/from Charles Keiley requesting information for proposed War History book by Virginia State Library, 1918 (Box 269, Folder 8)
    - Council of Defense (Box 270, Folder 1)
    - Council of Defense (Box 270, Folder 2)
    - Council of Defense - See Also Box 276
    - Education - Cooperative Education Association of Virginia: League Questionnaires (Box 270, Folder 3)
    - Form Letters (Box 270, Folder 4)
    - Form Letters (Box 270, Folder 5)
    - Form Letters (Box 270, Folder 6)
    - Form Letters (Box 270, Folder 7)
    - Forms, Blank (Box 270, Folder 8)
    - Forms - See Also Box 276
    - Health/Nursing (Box 271, Folder 1)
    - Health - Rural Sanitation (Box 271, Folder 2)
    - Health - Tuberculosis (Box 271, Folder 3)
    - Health - Tuberculosis (Box 271, Folder 4)
    - Labor (See Also Oversize) (Box 271, Folder 5)
    - Labor - See Also Box 276
    - Miscellaneous (Box 271, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 271, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 271, Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 272, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 272, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 272, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous (See Also Oversize Box 2) (Box 272, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 272, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 272, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 272, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 272, Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 272, Folder 9)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 273, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 273, Folder 2)
    - Other States - Arizona (Box 274, Folder 1)
    - Other States - California (See Also Box 276) (Box 274, Folder 2)
    - Other States - Colorado - See Box 276
    - Other States - Connecticut (See Also Box 276) (Box 274, Folder 3)
    - Other States - Florida (Box 274, Folder 4)
    - Other States - Georgia (Box 274, Folder 5)
    - Other States - Idaho (Box 274, Folder 6)
    - Other States - Illinois (Box 274, Folder 7)
    - Other States - Indiana (See Also Box 276) (Box 274, Folder 8)
    - Other States - Indiana (Box 274, Folder 9)
    - Other States - Iowa (Box 274, Folder 10)
    - Other States - Kansas (Box 274, Folder 11)
    - Other States - Maine - See Box 276
    - Other States - Maryland (See Also Box 276) (Box 274, Folder 12)
    - Other States - Massachusetts (See Also Box 276) (Box 275, Folder 1)
    - Other States - Minnesota (See Also Box 276) (Box 275, Folder 2)
    - Other States - New York (Box 275, Folder 3)
    - Other States - Ohio (Box 275, Folder 4)
    - Other States - Oklahoma (Box 275, Folder 5)
    - Other States - Oregon (Box 275, Folder 6)
    - Other States - Pennsylvania (See Also Box 276) (Box 275, Folder 7)
    - Other States - South Carolina (See Also Oversize Box 2) (Box 275, Folder 8)
    - Other States - South Dakota (See Also Box 276) (Box 275, Folder 9)
    - Other States - Texas (Box 275, Folder 10)
    - Other States - Utah (Box 275, Folder 11)
    - Other States - Vermont (Box 275, Folder 12)
    - Other States - Washington (Box 275, Folder 13)
    - Other States - West Virginia (Box 275, Folder 14)
    - Other States - Wisconsin (See Also Box 276) (Box 275, Folder 15)
    - Patriotism and Propaganda (Box 275, Folder 16)
    - Sugar (Box 275, Folder 17)
    - Unidentified (Box 275, Folder 18)
  - Oversize - Series XIV - Subseries B: Records
    - Council of Defense (Box 276, Folder 1)
    - Forms/Form Letters (Box 276, Folder 2)
    - Labor - "The Workman's Stake in the World War" (Box 276, Folder 3)
    - Other States - California (Box 276, Folder 4)
    - Other States - Colorado (Box 276, Folder 5)
    - Other States - Connecticut (Box 276, Folder 6)
    - Other States - Indiana (Box 276, Folder 7)
    - Other States - Maine (Box 276, Folder 8)
    - Other States - Maryland (Box 276, Folder 9)
    - Other States - Massachusetts (Box 276, Folder 10)
    - Other States - Minnesota (Box 276, Folder 11)
    - Other States - Pennsylvania (Box 276, Folder 12)
    - Other States - South Dakota (Box 276, Folder 13)
    - Other States - Wisconsin (Box 276, Folder 14)
  - Subseries C: Financial Records
    - Second Virginia Council of Defense/War History Commission - Bills, 1918-1919, A (Box 277, Folder 1)
    - Second Virginia Council of Defense/War History Commission - Bills, 1918-1919, B (Box 277, Folder 2)
    - Second Virginia Council of Defense/War History Commission - Bills, 1918-1919, C-P (Box 277, Folder 3)
    - Second Virginia Council of Defense/War History Commission - Bills, 1918-1919, R-V (Box 277, Folder 4)
    - Second Virginia Council of Defense/War History Commission - Bills, 1918-1919, W (Box 277, Folder 5)
  - Subseries D: Keiley, Charles R.
    - Correspondence, Personal - Keiley, Charles R., 1918-1919, A-B (Box 278, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, Personal - Keiley, Charles R., 1918-1919, C-D (Box 278, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, Personal - Keiley, Charles R., 1918-1919, E-G (Box 278, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, Personal - Keiley, Charles R., 1918-1919, H-J (Box 278, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, Personal - Keiley, Charles R., 1918-1919, K-N (Box 278, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, Personal - Keiley, Charles R., 1918-1919, P-S (Box 278, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, Personal - Keiley, Charles R., 1918-1919, T-W (Box 278, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, Personal - Keiley, Charles R., 1923-1924 (Box 278, Folder 8)
- Series XV: Margaret Ehtel Kelley Kern Papers, 1917-1925, 1928
  Margaret Ethel Kelly Kern was born 13 February 1874. Mrs. Kern did volunteer work for a variety of groups during World War I and was president of five World War I organizations: Richmond War Camp Community Service; Godmothers' League (founded by Kern on 17 September 1917); Women's Auxiliary; Women's Committee, Armistice Celebration; and the Service Legion (founded by Kern on 13 July 1921). Kern was also state chairman for the America First Committee. She married Dr. George Thomas Walker Kern (1873-1948), and they had one daughter, Margaret. Mrs. Kern died 10 July 1975 in Richmond, Virginia, and was buried in Hollywood Cemetery.
  The Margaret Ethel Kelley Kern Paper series is housed in 2 boxes and is arranged alphabetically by topic. Noteworthy records include: a membership list for the America First Committee and an account book for the Godmother's League (additional records on the Godmother's League can be found with the City of Richmond records within the City Source Material series). Significant materials include extensive material on the Service Legion. Founded on 13 July 1921 by Kern, the Service Legion, modeled on the American Legion, was created to commemorate civilian service during the war. Records include the constitution, by-laws and certificate of incorporation of the Service Legion; correspondence to and from Kern dated 1921-1924 & 1928 related to the Service Legion (additional correspondence can be found in the Office Files series); minutes of the Board of Directors of the Service Legion meeting on 5 April 1922; membership applications (including Kern, her husband and daughter) arranged alphabetically that list organizations and statement of state service during the war; and newspaper clippings describing Service Legion activities. Also included are the minutes of the Woman's Committee, Homecoming Jubilee Week, 22 April-1 July 1919, part of the group planning a homecoming celebration for returning troops in Richmond on 3 July-6 July 1919. The minute book also includes undated newspaper clippings on the committee's activities.
  - America First Committee - Membership List (Box 279, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1917-1920, 1925 (Box 279, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, General Letters and Clippings (Box 279, Folder 3)
  - Financial Records (Box 279, Folder 4)
  - Food Conservation - Richmond Kindergarten Association (Box 279, Folder 5)
  - Godmother's League - Account Book (Box 279, Folder 6)
  - Gold Star Honor Roll - City of Richmond (Box 279, Folder 7)
  - John Marshall High School - Patriotic Club (Box 279, Folder 8)
  - Publications - Copies of Publications forwarded by Mrs. G.T.W. Kern (Box 279, Folder 9)
  - Publications - Copies owned by Mrs. G.T.W. Kern (Box 279, Folder 10)
  - Publications - Copies owned by Mrs. G.T.W. Kern (Box 280, Folder 1)
  - Publications - Copies owned by Mrs. G.T.W. Kern (Box 280, Folder 2)
  - Records - Miscellaneous (Box 280, Folder 3)
  - Service Legion - By Laws and Certificate of Incorporation (Box 280, Folder 4)
  - Service Legion - Correspondence (Box 280, Folder 5)
  - Service Legion - Meeting Minutes (Box 280, Folder 6)
  - Service Legion - Membership Applications (Box 280, Folder 7)
  - Service Legion - Newspaper Clippings (Box 280, Folder 8)
  - Woman's Committee, Homecoming Jubilee Week - Minute Book (Box 280, Folder 9)
  - Woman's Committee, Homecoming Jubilee Week - Program and Correspondence (Box 280, Folder 10)
- Series XVI: H.R. McIlwaine Papers, 1919, 1921, 1928-1929 and 1931
  Henry Read McIlwaine was born 12 July 1864 in Prince Edward County, Virginia. He graduated with an A.B. from Hampden-Sidney College in 1885 and with a Ph.D. from Johns Hopkins University in 1893. McIlwaine taught in private schools for a few years before returning to Hampden-Sidney College to serve as professor of English and history. In 1907, he was appointed State Librarian for the Virginia State Library, which position he held until his death. In January 1919, Governor Westmoreland Davis appointed McIlwaine to the Virginia War History Commission where he held several positions including secretary of the Executive Committee, treasurer, and chairman of the War Letters, Diaries and Incidents section. Unmarried, he died 16 March 1934 in Richmond, Virginia, and was buried in Blandford Cemetery in Petersburg.
  The H.R. McIlwaine Papers series is housed in 1 box and consists primarily of incoming and outgoing correspondence to McIlwaine in his role as member of the Virginia War History Commission. Arranged by date, the majority of correspondence are from 1928-1929 and 1931 and concern purchasing copies of the Commission's publications. Correspondence are mainly from Arthur Kyle Davis, Russell B. Devine and William B. McIlwaine, Henry's cousin.
  - War History Commission, Correspondence, 1919 and 1921 (Box 281, Folder 1)
  - War History Commission, Correspondence, 1928-1929, 1931 (Box 281, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous Materials (Box 281, Folder 3)
  - Publications (Box 281, Folder 4)
- Series XVII: Miscellaneous Records, 1917-1921 (accession 28390)
  The Miscellaneous Records series is housed in 1 box and contains miscellaneous items including printed federal documents, ten letters of Helen Cameron written in France while doing War Relief Work during 1917 and 1918, extracts from General John Pershing's communications and brief histories of various army divisions. These records were accessioned separately on 3 October 1974.
  - Brief Histories of the Organization of Various Army Divisions - 57 items (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Letters of Helen Cameron, Written in France while doing War Relief Work, 1917-1918 - 10 items (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Extracts from General Pershing's Cabled Communiqués relating to various Army Divisions - 30 items (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - A list of officers who served as Military Attaches (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - U.S. Navy, Officers and Men who died during WWI (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous Printed Items and Photostats (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Series XVIII: Lynchburg City Committee Records, 1919-1921 (accession 33311)
  The Lynchburg City Committee Records series is housed in 1 box and contains Lynchburg's copies of its' Individual Service Records (questionnaires).
  - Questionnaires (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Series XIX: Prince Edward County Committee Records, 1919-1921 (accession 28057)
  The Prince Edward County Committee Records series is housed in 2 boxes and 1 oversize box and contains Prince Edward County's copies of its' Individual Service Records (questionnaires), lists of soldiers who served in the military, church and Red Cross information, and a report on post-war business conditions. The most significant item is a copy of the book, With "Old Eph" in the Army by Walker H. Jordan, published in 1919. Jordan, an African-American, describes his military experiences including his time in France.
  - Correspondence, 1919-1920 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Questionnaires - Colored (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Questionnaires - Colored (Home Service) (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Questionnaires - White (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Questionnaires - White (Overseas) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Questionnaires - White (Home Service) (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Churches (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Red Cross and Other Relief Organizations (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - List of Soldiers Overseas (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - List of Colored Troops Serving in France (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - List of Colored Draftees (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - List of White Volunteers and Draftees (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous Lists of Soldiers (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Farmville Herald Almanac, 1919 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Maps (see box 3 oversize) (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Newspaper Clippings (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Record of Hampden-Sidney Alumni in the World War (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Report on Post-War Business Conditions (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - With "Old Eph" in the Army by Walker H. Jordan, 1919 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Oversize - Maps (Box 3)
- Oversize - Series III: Virginia Military Organizations
  - Subseries A: 29th Division
    - Operations of the 29th Division, East of the Meuse River, October 1918 - Topographical Maps (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Subseries E: Miscellaneous and Correspondence
    - Chart Listing Virginia Military Units during World War (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Oversize - Series VIII: Selective Service and Volunteers
  - Subseries A: Induction Lists
    - Amelia County (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Bedford County (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Campbell County (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Giles County (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Goochland County (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Mecklenburg County (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Norfolk County (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Rockingham County (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - York County (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Lynchburg (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Subseries D: Miscellaneous
    - Selective Service Instructions and Eye Charts (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Oversize - Series XI: Office Files
  - Subseries A: Correspondence, General
    - Governor's Office, 1919-1927 (Budget Estimates) (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - History Commission - Chart of Members of Local Branches, ca. 1920 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Source Volumes - Advertisement for Volume II (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Subseries H: Publications
    - Newsletter, 1919-1920 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Oversize - Series XII: First Virginia Council of Defense
  - Scrapbook, 1917-1918 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Oversize - Series XIV: Second Virginia Council of Defense
  - Subseries A: Source Material
    - [Local Woman's Committees] (42a) - Two Isle of Wight County Broadsides (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Labor (48b) - two broadsides (labor and livestock) (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Subseries B: Records
    - Miscellaneous - War Information Poster from Council of Organizations for War Service (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Other States - South Carolina, Two Livestock Posters (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous and Bills (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Oversize - Series VI: County Source Material
  - Pittsylvania County
    - Pittsylvania County, Virginia, in the World War (contains all records collected by county, including letters, newspaper clippings, etc.) (Volume) (Box 3)
  - Greensville County
    - Miscellaneous - copy of Independent Messenger (9 March 1923) (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Oversize - Series VII: City Source Material
  - Harrisonburg
    - Post-War Conditions and Activities - copy of Harrisonburg Daily News-Record, 5 July 1924 (unveiling of American Legion Memorial) (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Petersburg
    - Economic and Social Conditions - Chamber of Commerce (16 January 1919 issue of Petersburg Progress) (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Portsmouth
    - War Letters, Diaries and Incidents - Neville, Wendell C. (clipping from Portsmouth Star, 14 March 1920) (Box 4, Folder 4)
- O versize - Series III: Virginia Military Organizations
  - Subseries D: Miscellaneous Units
    - Unit Photograph of 12th Aero Squadron, 1919, just back from France (Map-case 24, Drawer 10)